I am a backend web developer, with experience in frontend, currently based in Portugal. I take pride in writing clean and readable code. Besides web development my other programming interests include compilers, operating systems and software security. I have Portuguese citizenship and can work anywhere in the EU.

 $\begin{array}{lll} (+351) \ 920296829 & Linked In \\ \text{rk} 65536 @ \text{protonmail.com} & \text{GitHub} \\ \text{Porto, Portugal} & \text{Website} \end{array}$

Work Experience

INESC TEC, Porto, Portugal

February 2020 - Present

Backend (Research Grant) - Project is responsible for managing and implementing a security system for various DNA healthcare data backends. Responsible for

- Adding an authentication and authorization system to a backend (PHP Laravel, MongoDB, OIDC, UMA 2).
- Implementing a middleware server for managing access control for any backend compliant with the AIRR ADC API (Java Spring, Redis, Postgres, OIDC, UMA 2).
- Migrating a backend to the AIRR ADC API (python flask, mysql).

InvisibleCloud, Porto, Portugal

September 2018 - January 2020

Fullstack - The company's SaaS, InvisibleCollector, is a system for automated debt collection and settlement. As part of this product, was responsible for:

- Maintaining and extending the functionality of the admin panel's fontend and backend for managing the service (VueJS, Ruby on Rails).
- Maintaining and extending the functionality of the backend exposing a REST API (Java Dropwizard, MariaDB) and extending the clients using this API (C#, Go).
- Migrating a service for debtor and debtee communication and debt settlement to a new tech stack, from server-rendered ruby on rails to an SPA with VueJS and a REST API on Java dropwizard.

InvisibleCloud, Porto, Portugal

July 2018 - September 2018

Internship - The company's SaaS exposes a REST API which can be used by the company's clients to manage the product programmatically. As part of this service, was responsible for implementing and testing various REST HTTP client libraries in Java, C# and Go to ease the company client's integration with the API.

Research Centre in Real-Time & Embedded Computing Systems (CISTER) Porto, Portugal August 2017 - November 2017

Internship - Project's goal was to add support for real-time systems to the linux kernel. Was responsible for implementing and testing various real-time process schedulers on a modified Linux kernel running on ARM which involved extending kernel functionality (C and bash).

Education

Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto (FEUP)

Porto, Portugal. 2015 - 2020

 $Integrated\ Masters$ - Informatics and Computing Engineering (Software Engineering) Grade Average: 17/20

Personal Projects

Many more smaller projects on my GitHub.

• Personal Blog Website:

A small, mobile friendly, website intended to run a developer's blog, running on Django. source code

• Android Sound Editor Application:

A Sound Editor/Mixer Android Application written on C# with Xamarin. Developed with a heavy emphasis on code structure and readability (OO design principles). Google Play Store: RMixer, Source

• Mobile Game Application:

An aplication written with Kivy on Python with a native physics 'engine' to simulate bullet trajectories affected by gravitational fields. source code

Skills

Experience	2 weeks to 3 months	3 months to 1 year	1 year or more
Languages	x86_64 Assembly,	C, C++, Go, Type-	Java, Python, SQL,
	Scala, Rust	script, SASS	HTML, CSS, PHP,
			Bash scripting, Ruby,
			C#
Libraries &	ReactJS, Keras, Ten-	Django, Xamarin, Lar-	VueJS, Dropwizard,
Frameworks	sorFlow, nodeJS,	avel, ASP.NET	Rails
	gRPC, Protobuff,		
	openCV, Android Java		
	API		
Tools & Ser-	AWS, Terraform, Re-	nginx, Post-	git, Linux, Docker
vices	dis, Kafka, mongoDB	gres, SQLite,	
		MySQL/MariaDB	

Spoken Languages